## Nazmus Sakib

Montreal, Quebec, Canada. H3W 1W2 🏫

+1 (514) 621-4478

sakibn55@gmail.com

https:/www.linkedin.com/in/nazmus-insakib-531997a9

https://github.com/sakibn55 #

https://nazmus.netlify.app

https://www.fiverr.com/nazmussakib680 \\ \mathref{m}

I am a full stack developer with over 3 years of experience. I have developed and maintained complex Web and RESTful applications using PHP, Laravel, MySQL and JavaScript along with various other technologies. I always love working with technically strong team where I can solve complex problems with a good balance of freedom and responsibility.

## **Key Skills**

- HTML
- JavaScript
- VueJs
- PHP
- C#
- CakePHP
- Agile
- Object-Oriented Programming
- Communication Skills
- Technical Skills
- Critical Thinking Skills

- CSS
- jQuery
- MySQL
- Laravel
- Drupal
- Git
- Time Management Skills
- Problem Solving Skills
- Project Management Skills
- Analytical Thinking Skills
- English Proficiency

## **Education**

2019 - 2021

# Attestation of College Studies (A.C.S) Diploma CDI College, Montreal, Canada

Programmer Analyst/Internet Solution Developer

#### **Bachelor of Science**

## Leading University, Sylhet, Bangladesh

- Computer Science and Engineering
- Graduated with 3.09 CGPA
- Joint secretary of Leading University Computer Club

2012

## **Higher Secondary School Certificate**

## Brindaban Govt. College, Habiganj, Sylhet, Bangladesh

- Science
- Graduated with 4.40 GPA

2010

## **Secondary School Certificate**

## Govt. High School, Habiganj, Sylhet, Bangladesh

- Science
- Graduated with 5.00 GPA

## **Work Experience**

DECEMBER 2021 - PRESENT

## Laravel Developer/ Giving Gateway, Toronto, ON (Remote)

- Working on a Donation App where Donors can donate on Campaigns on a Installment, Monthly and One time Donation Basis.
- Design, code and debug applications in Laravel
- Software analysis, code analysis, requirements analysis, software review
- Identification of code metrics, system risk analysis
- Build RESTful API

#### JANUARY 2021 - MAY 2021

#### Laravel Developer / LSA Education Canada

• Developed Client WEB applications by applying experience in Laravel MVC Framework. [https://www.lsaeducation.com]

#### SEPTEMBER 2018 - SEPTEMBER 2019

## Jr. Software Engineer / SJ INNOVATION LLC

- Developed WEB applications by applying experience in Drupal, PHP, Laravel, CakePHP, and JavaScript.
- Took the lead of a team of 7 to maintain and deliver 350+ projects for Janssen & Janssen and Janssen Medical Cloud UK and Ireland. [https://www.janssenmedicalcloud.co.uk/, https://www.janssenmedicalcloud.ie/]
- Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs and enhancements
- Gathered and defined customer requirements to develop clear specifications for creating well-organized project plans
- Analyzed code defects and failures and presented code refactors and design fixes
- Tuned and improved software source code based upon new user requirements and technical guidelines
- Followed Agile Method
- Contributed to daily scrum meetings with team updates

#### APRIL 2018 - SEPTEMBER 2018

## Software Engineer Internship / SJ INNOVATION LLC

- Debugging and testing code
- Documenting and testing new software applications
- Researching, investigating and fixing a wide range of technical issues
- Collaborating with senior leaders
- Approaching problems and creating solutions

Proactively learning about new technologies

## **Other Work Experience**

2020 - PRESENT

## Self-Employment/Fiverr.com/nazmussakib680

- Working as Part-Time
- Completed 20+ Project

## **Training**

- LICT Top-Up IT Training
  - Duration: 300rs Year 2017
  - o Batch code: LICT\_TUP\_LUSYL\_01\_WebDev
  - o portal.bdskills.com/certificates
  - o Graduate ID: G026124
- Drupal Training
  - o SJ Innovation LLC

## **Honors & Awards**

- Performer of the month
  - o Honor date: July 2019
  - o Honor issuer: SJ INNOVATION LLC
- Performer of the month
  - Honor date: February 2019
  - o Honor issuer: SJ INNOVATION LLC

## **Volunteer Experience**

- Joint Secretary
  - o Leading University Computer Club
  - o Jan 2017 Jan 2018
  - Science and Technology
  - o Organized programming contests, gaming contests, tech workshops.

## References

#### • Abubakar Choudhury

- o CPA Canada
- o CFO AT LSA Education
- o https://www.linkedin.com/in/abubakarchoudhury/
- o +1 (514) 715-7274 (CA)

#### Shahed Islam

- o Co-Founder And CEO of SJ Innovation LLC
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/sjinnovation/
- o +1(718)781-4451(US)